Guide to the A. Bartlett Giamatti, President of Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
A. Bartlett Giamatti, president of Yale University, records
1975-1993
RU 276
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
218.25
(333 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, annual reports, memoranda, subject files, and gifts documenting A. Bartlett Giamatti's tenure as president of Yale.
Yale University. President's Office
Giamatti, A. Bartlett, 1938-1989
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 2-A (YRG 2-A), Records of the Yale president's office.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Biographical / Historical
Angelo Bartlett Giamatti was born on April 4, 1938 in Boston, Massachusetts. He attended Yale College (B.A. 1960) and Yale Graduate School (Ph.D. 1964). After earning his doctorate, Giamatti taught Italian and comparative literature at Princeton University (1964-1966). He went on to teach English and comparative literature at Yale (1966-1977). In 1976 he became the Frederick Clifford Ford Professor of English and Comparative Literature, and in 1977 he accepted the John Hay Whitney Professorship of English and Comparative Literature. In 1978, Giamatti became president of Yale, a position he held until his resignation in 1986.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, annual reports, memoranda, subject files, and gifts documenting A. Bartlett Giamatti's tenure as president of Yale.
Universities and colleges -- Administration; College presidents; Educators; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Presidents; Yale University. President's Office
- Posters for speeches on the role of the federal government in higher education, circa 1985; Accession 19ND-A-425
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - Posters (2) for speeches on the role of the federal government in higher education, circa 1985 (Folder 1)
- Letter to Gerry Wynkoop and A. Bartlett Giamatti from Charles Dibble concerning the 100th Yale-Harvard football game, 1983; Accession 1983-A-092
  - Letter to Gerry Wynkoop and A. Bartlett Giamatti from Charles Dibble concerning the 100th Yale-Harvard football game, 1983 (Box 1)
- "Confessions of an Amatore Dantesco", 1982; Accession 1983-A-093
  - "Confessions of an Amatore Dantesco," gift of Morris Gitlitz, 1982 (Box 1)
- Inauguration material of A. Bartlett Giamatti, 1978-1993; Accession 1999-A-079
  - Inauguration of A. Bartlett Giamatti (Press Kit), 1978 (Box 1)
  - Baseball Commissioner, Appointment (Box 1)
  - "The Giamatti Files," New Haven Advocate, 1993 May 6 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous articles, 1989 March - 1990 April (Box 1)
  - Inauguration (Box 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings
    - 1989 Nov -1990 Jan (Box 1)
    - 1989 Sep -1990 Oct (Box 1)
- Records and scrapbooks documenting A. Bartlett Giamatti, circa 1977-1983; Accession 2004-A-069
  - Scrapbooks documenting President Giamatti, circa 1977-1983 (Box 2)